Samim Saim

Kabul, Afghanistan 1001 | (+93) 744-965-268 | Samim.saim1212@gmail.com

Summary

An experienced web developer with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from Kabul Polytechnic University, Kabul, Afghanistan, My experience spans across several industries with a total of 3 years hands on experience. I am hardworking and a good collaborator with high level understanding of software and database development with a lot of flexibility in picking up new technologies.

Educations

DECEMBER 2018

Kabul Polytechnic University, Kabul, Afghanistan-Bachelor's in Computer Science.

DECEMBER 2013

Saveed Hussain High School, Kabul, Afghanistan-Diploma in Secondary Higher Education.

Skills

Python, Java, JavaScript, react.js, angular.js, HTML5, Css3, PHP, PHP(codeigniter, Laravel) ASP.NET, Nodejs, SQL Server, MySQL, Mongodb, Spark.

Projects

Contact Management System – A web-app that manages personal contact information.

• Frontend built by ReactJs and backend Nodejs.

Fleet Management System – A full stack software project to keep track of company vehicles

• Frontend built by Angular and backend Asp.Net.

Dormitory Management System – A MIS(management information system) that manage information of all students of universities

• Frontend built by Bootstrap, CSS5, HTML5 and backend PHP(Codeigniter)

Library Management System – A MIS(management information system) that manage information of all the books and students of the Kabul polytechnic university.

• Frontend built by Bootstrap, CSS5, HTML5 and backend PHP(Lravel)

Experiences

SEPTEMBER 2020 - present

Ministry of Energy and Water (MEW) – MIS Expert

- Design and develop web and MIS application.
- Testing and solving the applications problems.
- Train the other staffs.

MAY 2019 – AUGUST 2020

Ministry of Education (MOE) – Database and Web Developer

- Design and develop web application if needed.
- Testing and solving the applications problems.
- Helping other employees to know about new applications.

AUG - 2018 – 30 - DECEMBER - 2018

Elitech Tech Company – Web Developer & Web Designer

- Creating MIS for a private and public hospital, Universities.
- Upgrading and maintaining the systems.
- Teaching and training web Designing and developing courses.

21 AUGUST 2017 – 18 NOVEMBER 2017

NPA (National procurement Authority) — Web developer, Intern

- Design web according to requirement which was gathered by manager.
- Developing web, using Laravel, material design, and jQuery.
- Using SQL server in backend.